

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





PRASAD DELHI

Senior Lead Engineer with 14+ years of experience in JAVA backend applications along with experience in Design, Development with technologies like Microservices, Vertx, AWS, Spring, MongoDB, Oracle, Solr etc.

Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Current Designation: Senior Leader Engineer
Current Company: Unisys (via Trigent Software)
Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Leader Engineer, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Design Development, Requirement Gathering, Technical Analysis, Jenkins, Core Java, Spring

Framework, Microservices, Oracle, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Solr

Verified : C Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Have 14+ years of IT experience in Software Analysis, Design, Development and Unit Testing using Java/J2EE and its related technologies.

Expertise in JAVA technologies and handled projects which involved extensive usage of Core JAVA, Microservices, Spring Framework, SOAP/RESTful API, AWS, Jenkins, etc.

Experience in working as a Technical Lead in multi-vendor environment as well as an individual contributor.

Experience in working on various domains such as Banking, Insurance, Airline, Healthcare.

Good Understanding of RDBMS through Database Design, writing queries and stored procedures using databases like Oracle, Postgres.

Work Experience

 Unisys (via Trigent Software) as Senior Leader Engineer Feb 2019 to Till Date

Designed, developed and converted monolithic legacy product into microservices oriented architecture. Leading team and guiding them with Development. Introduced methodologies and best practices to enhance product definition and application customization. Involved in development, unit testing, and automation testing of APIs as an individual contributor

U.S. Bank as Senior Application Developer Jul 2018 to Feb 2019

Designed and developed SOAP based APIs that are both consumed and produced by several internal and external applications.

Lead team upfront in implementing and adapting to new methodologies such as TDD and Automation Testing. Involved in development, unit testing, and automation testing of APIs.

Designed and developed batch jobs using Spring Batch.

Evolent Health LLC as Senior Software Engineer Jun 2017 to Jul 2018

Designed and developed modules in the application that is used by operations team.

Involved in designing and development of parsing huge patient data files



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Silicon Institute of Technology, Bhuvaneshwar in 2006

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
JAVA		
Oracle		
Mongodb		
MicroServices		
SPRING FRAMEWORK		
AWS		
RabbitMQ		
HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT		
Apache Solr		
Vert.x		
SAFE		
SOAP, RESTful API		
JUNITS		
MAVEN, GRADLE		
Jenkins		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Expert	✓		✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

US Work Status: **Have H1 Visa** Job Type: **Permanent** Employment Status: **Full time**

Work Authorization

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.